

jessicajzhong@gmail.com

650-255-2187



linkedin.com/in/jessicazhong



jessicazhong.design

## **SUMMARY**

A Product Designer with a business acumen focused on people. I am committed to creating better user experiences through a deep understanding of people by identifying real-life problems and crafting thoughtful solutions grounded by research

## **EDUCATION**

#### **BLOC.IO**

**UX/UI** Design Apprenticeship Nov 2018 - current

# UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA **SAN DIEGO**

**B.S Management Science** 

# **RECENT PROJECT**

### **HEALTHPOINT | MOBILE APPLICATION**

jessicazhong.design/project1.html

- A cloud-based mobile application that provides health enthusiasts an improved way to collect and store data, with the ability to analyze, connect and organize in the palm of their hand
- Utilized Sketch, Figma, Draw.io to create user flows, wireframes, mockups, usability testing and branding work

## **SKILLS**

#### **DESIGN**

**UX/UI** Design Visual Design **User Research Usability Testing Brand Design & Identity** Information Architecture Wireframing **Prototyping** Sketching

#### **DESIGN TOOLS**

Sketch

**Figma** 

UsabilityHub

**InVision** 

**Affinity Designer** 

Draw.io

Maze

#### **WEB DEVELOPMENT**

**HTML** 

CSS

JavaScript (basic)

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **BLOC.IO** | UX/UI APPRENTICESHIP

Nov 2018 - Current

- Completing a 500+ hour immersive project-based online bootcamp under the mentorship of a senior UX professional
- Applying all design methodologies from user research, wireframes, mockups to functional prototypes using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Conducting user interviews and usability tests to gather feedback for creation of personas and iterations
- Developing brand identities, such as name, logo and style guide

## **JOBVITE** | HR GENERALIST

Apr 2017 - Jan 2019

- Spearheaded company's first Wellness Initiative, resulting in a 45% participation rate for the first year, across all programs for a company of 195 employees
- Implemented a candidate and new hire survey into Jobvite's platform to analyze tangible data regarding the health of Jobvite's brand and candidate experience
- Owned all aspects of onboarding new hire orientation, employment authorization, benefits enrollment to ensure a great employee onboarding experience

## **MOODY'S CORPORATION** | HR ASSOCIATE

Apr 2014 - Apr 2017

- Developed solutions for tasks related to employee relations, organizational restructuring, performance evaluations and operations
- Interpreted HR metrics and reporting analysis to create an evolving employee narrative for managers